this was when everybody said they
thought Iran had attacked Saudi Arabia
this was from MSNBC it said just in
American intelligence shows that the
attack on a major Saudi oil facility was
launched from Iran three people familiar
with the intelligence tell NBC News now
that's NBC News just repeating what the
CIA tells them they just yes so that's
just so that's not news so that that's
the thing like so that way my shows on
YouTube so when a breaking news story
like this happens YouTube now their
algorithm pushes you to places they
consider what they called a trusted
media news sources like MSNBC or so this
is complete bull this is yet what
they're doing is pushing you towards the
CIA talking points and YouTube was
supposed to be the antidote to that and
it isn't anymore when it comes to
breaking news but at least we get to do
it after the fact so that's why I'm
doing it I'm showing you this is
complete fake news and so when Trump
that's the thing - so when Trump says
fake news it lands because most of what
the corporate news does is fake news
especially when it comes to foreign
policy and war right so so today soot
from from CNN tweeted in the aftermath
of that attack so I guess again mr.
president you're not gonna do anything
and I tweeted at him and I said if you
have evidence real intelligence that the
Iranians were behind this you have a
duty to let us know what it is otherwise
keep your neoliberal war mongering
opinions to yourself and then he
responded but all he said was I never
advocated going to war ah so you know
what's crazy John is that everybody was
afraid that it was Trump who is gonna be
the maniac it was supposed to be Trump
who was gonna be the guy we can't allow
him near the button and it everybody's
encouraging Trump to do more bombing
yeah everybody is and the intelligence
is not there you know as a as a trained
CIA analyst
we were not allowed to make an analytic
judgment without the evidence and
there's no evidence they can't say like
they've been saying they can't say take
our word for it or my favorite one if
you knew what I know yeah you saw the
intelligence that I've seen you would
agree nonsense I worked there for 15
years I know you guys just make it up
and that's what they do they make it up
so I so I want to play this for people
this is a minute and a half long and
this is them announcing they're sending
troops to Saudi Arabia okay here we go
the United States has a responsibility
to protect our citizens and our interest
in the region and the international
community has a responsibility to
protect the global in a the global
economy and international rules and
norms he almost said they have to
protect the global inequality it's a he
almost said that he didn't but he was
that close okay here we go well this is
threatened by Iran's significant
escalation of violence this week I've
been in dialog with the Saudi defense
minister and other partners about this
latest attack to prevent further
escalation Saudi Arabia requested
international support to help protect
the kingdom's critical infrastructure
the United Arab Emirates has also
requested assistance in response to the
kingdom's request the president has
approved the deployment of US forces
which will be defensive in nature and
primarily focused on air and missile
defense we will also work to accelerate
the delivery of military equipment to
the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the UAE
to enhance their ability to defend
themselves the purpose of the additional
defensive support we will provide is as
follows first to send a clear message
that the United States supports our
partners in the region second to ensure
the free flow of resources necessary to
support the global economy and third to
demonstrate our commitment to upholding
the international rules based order that
we have long called on Iran to obey the
last one for the and they don't even say
used to say spreading democracy and
they don't even say that anymore so then
even bother so what he what he just said
was we're there just to support Saudi
Arabia cuz they're our pals and make
sure that oil keeps flowing around the
world and the third one is is to make
sure everybody plays by the rules you
know we're the ones that we just drop we
just turn Libya into a failed state with
slave trading we just killed a million
people in Iraq the country right next
door to Iran we said trying to do the
same thing in Syria we try where it
we're the ones who are we're the ones
who are the biggest violators we just
killed 30 pine nut farmers in
Afghanistan two days ago we're the ones
who are violating international norms
and the terrorists so that's why it's
funny that he said we're doing this
again nowhereness to help people or to
say it's just because Saudi Arabia is
our buddy he doesn't say why Saudi
Arabia is our buddy
he just says they are we got to keep the
oil flowing and we got to make sure they
follow the rules which so all three of
those are and so I like what
this guy says and let me get this
straight its 2020 and we're putting our
forces in danger to babysit some
medieval kingdom that treats women like
chattel witch saws up journalists which
has substantial involvement in the 9/11
attacks and which has its own military
equipped with our weapons so didn't
Trump just sell them 110 billion dollars
worth of weapons what the hell is why do
they need us to defend them and if you
remember if you voted for Trump because
he was an anti interventionist because
he would say stuff like this
he would say Saudi Arabia should fight
their own Wars which they won't or pay
us an absolute fortune to protect them
and their great wealth trillion so he
doesn't do that now he just said they
asked so we're gonna send them they're
nice people so if you want to impeach
Trump it should be over being in bed
with a murderous dictator who dismembers
journalists and is now committing a
genocide in Yemen that Trump is helping
yes so no that's why you and peachy guy
you noted peachy guy because he wanted
to look into the corruption of Joe
Biden's kid who was actually corrupt
yeah he was actually
there's actually something to it you
know let me tell you a little bit about
Saudi Arabia to Saudi Arabia was the
first foreign foreign tour that I ever
did as a young junior 25 year old CIA
officer
I just wrote about this in consortium
news last week and I said I was so
excited to go the Iraqis had just
crossed the Kuwaiti border and they and
they took Kuwait and I was sent to Saudi
Arabia to sort of babysit the Saudi
royal family which was my area of
expertise at the time I was so excited
every day I would walk to the American
embassy in Riyadh from a little
apartment that they put me in in the
diplomatic quarter and the the embassy
was reigned by Saudi guards so every day
I would say to the guard I said ah boy I
like him may peace be upon you and he
would ignore me the the response is
supposed to be war like oh my Salaam and
upon you peace but he would ignore me
and I would do this every day just to
see if he would say something when I was
going to the embassy and then leaving
from the embassy assalamu alaikum and he
would ignore me so one day I said to him
what's your problem and he was
ready with a response and he said you
are hired help we hired you to come here
and to protect the oil fields we paid
you money you're not here because we're
friends you're here because we bought
you so don't expect thanks and he was
exactly right he was right we are hired
help to them they're not doing this out
of the goodness their hearts they want
to buy our weapons to keep Americans
working and keep our factories open
that's all they don't care one
whit about us and another thing too and
this is something that Americans just
don't know is that there are no Saudi
nationals in the Saudi military except
at the highest ranks that is Lieutenant
Colonel and higher they're all
Pakistanis they're hired help and so
that's what we're fighting alongside
over there so you think
any mercenaries that's right because the
people of Saudi Arabia will join their
own military just like back here in the
United States they have to create a
financial crisis for it so people will
join the military that's we just did a
story about that that the student loan
crisis is the thing fueling the military
recruitment it's nothing it's not people
wanting to serve their country or fight
communism or terrorism or it's people
who don't have any other financial
options so the same things happening in
Saudi Arabia is they can't get anybody
to join their military so they're also
trying to create this Yemen crisis this
has to fold it cashes in the check that
the United States has to come support
them they they wanted to test us that's
what Yemen is them testing us also EJ
could create a crisis so they go you got
to join the military we got a crisis
right so back to you nobody will take
those jobs you know I said I went to I
used to go on weekends to OPM saying
that's the Saudi Arabian National Guard
believe it or not because they sell pork
there so if I wanted bacon or sausage
I'd have to go to the Saudi National
Guard commissary to buy my pork and go
back to the diplomatic quarter and I
used to say hi to the soldier all the
time Muhammad and I would really
struggle to understand what the heck
this guy was saying because my Arabic
was okay at the time it wasn't great and
finally I said to one of the guys at the
Embassy I have a hell of a time
understanding anything that Mohammed
says he said Mohammed who I said
Mohammed at OPM saying he said Mohamed
doesn't speak Arabic I said what are you
talking about he said he's from Pakistan
he's speaking Urdu he doesn't know how
to speak Arabic there are no Saudis over
there at the Saudi National Guard
they're all Pakistanis and that's how I
learned so here we go so I want to show
people this just so again the Democrats
are going to completely blow the
impeachment thing because they're
looking at something there it's too
narrow in focus and the things they
should be a beating up over there both
complicit in right that's that's why
Nancy why do you think Nancy Pelosi
didn't want to impeach George Bush and
Dick Cheney or and and had to hold those
hearings because
was clear they were war criminals and it
was clear they lied us into a war and
the reason why is because they were
smarter than Nancy Pelosi because in
2002 when they started torturing people
they told her about it and she didn't
tell anybody else which makes her
complicit in a war crime which would it
came out if they had an impeachment
hearing which is why she said
impeachment is off the table
absolutely right that's why we need a
third party in this country at least a
viable one that we have are all liars
they're both liars and and and if
they're in bed one party when it comes
to foreign policy and here's John Kerry
and he's gonna admit to you the deal we
have with Saudi Arabia so the one thing
people don't talk about and I showed you
here let me just show you this I said
I'm offering 1 million dollars for the
first corporate newsreader to mention
the petrol dollar while reporting that
we are sending Americans to protect
Saudi oil note that by the way that
money still unclaimed no takers
still unclaimed that money is still
unclaimed just like when Andy Kindler
offered a million dollars anybody who
could produce a tape of Whoopi Goldberg
saying something funny 20 years later
still unclaimed that million that was
blamed anyway here it is nobody took me
up on that and let me just quickly
explain to people what the petrodollar
is and why were in bed with Saudi Arabia
as opposed to Iran which is a mistake
the petrol dollars when we went off the
gold standard in the 70s
Saudi Arabia made a deal with us that
everybody would have to monetize if they
wanted to buy oil that do it with the
United States dollar so whatever their
currency was they'd have first convert
it to US dollars buy it and then they
took a lot of their oil profits and they
buy our securities and they own a lot of
our Treasuries and all that stuff so
that's what the petrol dollar is at its
artificially propping up our economy and
our dollar and that's why a lot of
people speculated that part of the
motivation the screwing up Libya was
Qaddafi was one to go out of dinar when
to go off the petro dollar the whole
deal also there's now there's gonna be a
petrol Yang and people are talking about
um yeah that's not it yang what am I
talking about yin yang I got Andrew yang
on my mind it's $1,000 a month and yang
fedra dollars a thousand dollars that's
funny so anyway that's the thing people
don't realize and and that's why I when
they said it was okay when they passed
that law to make it okay to sue Saudi
Arabia over 9/11 Barack Obama had to fly
to Saudi Arabia to calm everybody down
because dope that would truly screw up
our economy and so that's why we're in
bed with people like Saudi Arabia also
the CIA they preferred dictatorships
over democracies which is why they are
in bed with Saudi Arabia and they
overthrew Mosaddegh in the 50s who was
the democratically elected president of
Iran the CIA instituted a coup to
overthrow him because he wanted to keep
the oil for his own people and he wanted
to spread democracy around democracy is
hard to control CIA wants to get rid of
democracies in the Middle East replaced
them with the theocrats and then
dictators cuz they're easier to control
which is why we're in bed with right now
a neo-nazi organization in the Ukraine
and the Saudi Arabia's in the Med so
that that's how this works right and
nobody gets impeached over installing a
Nazi regime in Ukraine nobody get some
pizza over committing a genocide in
Yemen but somebody gets impeached
because they tried to say they tried to
go after their political opponent in a
bad way that's and by the way that's not
gonna fly he's not gonna give him
peached it's gonna bolster him just like
Russia his highest approval ratings came
after Russia gate and now nobody
believes the mainstream media the
Democrats attacks especially when it
comes to something like this who Joe
Biden's kid is corrupt in it all right
so let me just get to this here I want
to show here's respect too so here is
John Kerry and he's gonna he's gonna
tell you what's really happening with
Saudi Arabia and this is in front of a
congressional committee countries
offering to do respect to Arab
country's offering to bear cost and to
assess the answer is profoundly yes they
have that offer is on the table
so he's talking about going into Syria
that's when they were trying to get us
to everybody was that big push to
overthrow Assad and Barack Obama had the
line in the sand and all that stuff and
so he's saying hey yeah with respect to
our Arab friends
he means Saudi Arabia they've offered to
pay the price for us to overthrow Syria
here we go with respect to boots on the
ground profoundly no there will be no
boots on the ground the president has
said that again and again and there is
nothing in this authorization that
should contemplate it so he's saying we
could do it the same way we did Libya no
boots on the ground we'll just bomb the
out of everybody and turn it into a
failed state we'll get somebody to put a
bayonet up Assad and then we'll give it
we'll get our own what we'll turn it
over to Isis who's in bed with Saudi
Arabia funded by Saudi Arabia and
they'll run the country which is what's
happening and so here we go the we
reiterate no boots on the ground in
terms of what do you do doesn't work I
think I'll let general Dempsey speak to
the question of targeting as which he
can't go into in detail but we have
absolute confidence that what our
military undertakes to do if it is
ordered to do so will degrade the
capacity of Assad to use these weapons
and and serve as a very strong
deterrence and if it doesn't then there
are subsequent possibilities as to how
you could reinforce that Thank You mr.
secretary secretary and the the here
comes the key question details on the
offer and the proposal on the table what
what are the figures that we're talking
about so what is the offer from Saudi
Arabia what is their financial offer for
us if we go and overthrow Assad for it
for them what is that what are they
offering and he says well we don't know
what action we're engaged in right now
but they've been quite significant I
mean
very significant some of them have said
that if the United States is prepared to
go do the whole thing the way we've done
it previously in other places they'll
carry that cost that's how dedicated
they are does so that you heard that's
that's when he's Secretary of State said
Saudi Arabia's willing to pay for our
entire war if we overthrow Assad that's
how dedicated they are to it that's how
much the pipeline that they want to send
through Syria is worth to them that's
what that's about that's the part they
don't tell you why do you want to do
this for them why do you care why do you
care about Syria John Kerry why do you
want to overthrow Assad why are you
pretending you care about people
oh it's cuz Saudi Arabia wants to put a
pipeline through so they can also sell
natural gas to Europe and they can
compete with Russia I got it okay no one
tells you that you know tells you that
Jackass comedians on YouTube
that's who tell you that right and my by
the way John am I wrong about that no
you're totally right and what he what he
meant by that statement was that the
Saudis are willing to pay for the last
American soldier to go to his death in
Saudi Arabia they'll pay for as long as
we want to send our men our young men
and women to face their deaths in a
middle-eastern desert no problem yeah
that's exactly what in fact here's
WikiLeaks has revealed he had been
waiting a long time to hear what Browne
told him subsequent statements by brown
secretary Schlesinger and others have
led to the Saudis to believe that we
have offered them virtually a blank
check for their security needs Brown
subsequent statement in Israel plus the
present stalemate at the peace talks
have again injected a note of skepticism
into the Saudi minds they have decided
that there is no better time or
opportunity to see if the u.s. check is
good and how much money is in the
account and that's what's happening in
Yemen and so that's what's going on and
here here is Julian Assange to let us
know that when we're in bed with Saudi
Arabia we're literally in bed with Isis
okay now we've showed you how we were in
bed with Isis in Libya we showed you how
we're in bed was in Syria and of course
the Washington Post and CNN smear
for telling the truth about that and
here's julian assange to tell you have
helped create there's a early 2014 email
from hillary clinton so not so long
after she left Secretary of State to her
campaign manager John Podesta that email
it states that ISIL Isis is funded by
Saudi Arabia and Qatar the governments
of Saudi Arabia and Qatar now this is a
actually I think this is the most
significant email in the whole
collection and perhaps because Saudi and
Qatari money is spread all over the
place including including into many
media institutions all serious analysts
know even the US government has
mentioned or agreed with that some Saudi
figures have been supporting Isis
funding Isis but the Dodge has always
been that's what it's just some rogue
princes using their cut of the oil money
to do what they like but actually the
government disapproves but that email
says that no it is the governments of
Saudi and the government or in Qatar
that have been funding Isis the Saudi so
there you go that email reveals that
it's the government of Saudi Arabia that
is literally funding Isis not rogue
Prince's with their share of the oil
money which is what people have said
before again this doesn't get reported
even when we're sending troops to Saudi
Arabia the people reporting that don't
tell you about this they don't tell you
that Saudi Arabia is in bed with Isis
they don't tell you they're committing
of genocide in Yemen and we're helping
them they don't tell you anything
nothing which is why we have Donald
Trump as president they also don't tell
you that al Qaeda is now called an
Isetta front
in since Syria and that we are funding
them and arming them we don't call them
al-qaeda anymore we call the Minnesota
yeah that's right there's there's a lot
that our government isn't telling us or
there's a lot that our government is
lying about to us visa the Saudi Arabia
at the war in Syria the war in Libya the
war in Yemen the warrior the war there
they're just lying to us and isn't it
sad to see like that's why I think it's
so important that Tulsi Gabbard is in
those debates because she's the one who
stood up to Trump and said we are we are
soldiers were not your and we're
not we don't work for Saudi Arabia
you're not our pimp we're not
prostitutes she laid it out like in
nobody's business right and she's a
soldier but she's a medic right which is
what I like about her and so that's why
it's great that she's because Bernie as
great as he is on domestic policy his
Achilles heel is foreign policy and he
often repeats CIA talking points and I'm
a big Bernie backer but that's his
that's his blind spot and I think she
really fills it in perfectly would you
agree I agree completely and that's why
I was so thrilled that she she met the
DNC's phony numbers to make the next
debate because we really need Tulsi
Gabbard in that debate I agree with you
about Bernie Sanders I love Bernie
Sanders you know when I was working on
Capitol Hill I used to I used to do the
same thing every day I I'd walk to the
office I'd boot up my computer and while
it was booting up I'd go down to the
cafeteria and get a cup of coffee and
every single day there was Bernie
Sanders sitting at a table inviting
literally anybody who walked in to have
breakfast with him sit at the table and
the only thing he insisted on was that
you call him Bernie so I love Bernie
Sanders he's one of us but he does have
an Achilles heel and it's foreign policy
yeah John Kerry aku who was the host of
loud and clear on Sputnik radio also
he's a columnist for reader supported
news anyplace else we should tell them
to go check you out at Jon Consortium
news they've been very very good to me
okay fantastic John Kerry akio you're
always welcome thanks for sharing your
opinions with us and your insight thanks
so much I love the show and I love being
on thank you okay
everybody we're doing a live show every
Sunday in October in Hollywood
California at the Sycamore tavern go to
jimmy dore comedy calm for a link for
tickets and become a patron we give you
hours of bonus material every month
become a Premium Member go to jimmy dore
comedy comm and sign up thanks for your
support
[Music]